# JUSTIN NALDZIN

DATA ENGINEER -

215 - 307 - 6449



justinnaldzin@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/justinnaldzin



justinnaldzin.github.io



Philadelphia, Pennsylvania



# PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

A driven data engineer experienced in identifying deficiencies, implementing corrective solutions to reduce production impact and supporting systems and applications critical to operational workflow. Areas of focus include operational intelligence, cloud infrastructure monitoring and alerting, business intelligence, data visualization and analytics, scripting and automation.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### DATA ENGINEER

Penn Medicine | Philadelphia | November 2016 - Present

The Data Analytics Center is responsible for ensuring 100's of terabytes of Penn Medicine's healthcare data reaches partner organizations, internal vendor applications, local/state/federal government institutions, and research collaborators.

- · Created a portable, reproducible, and fully automated application designed to benchmark various database platforms and big data technologies
- Statistical analysis on medical claims using Spark to understand patient demographics
- Migrate 100+ billion rows of access logs into Hadoop
- · Geocoding of patients, providers, and facilities using Google Maps API to measure distances and understand patients' behaviors

### PRODUCT DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

Comcast | Philadelphia | October 2015 - November 2016

A member of a DevOps team responsible for the operations and infrastructure of the XFINITY On Demand ingest, encoding/packaging, quality control and publishing workflows delivering QAM and IP video to XfinityTV.com, Xfinity.com, mobile iOS/Android apps and various connected devices in the home.

- Develop a real-time network infrastructure monitoring and alerting system
- Produce complex, recurring and ad-hoc reports and dashboards with the purpose of measuring progress towards goals, performance against objectives, as well as identifying improvement opportunities
- Collaborate with the Architecture team on continuous integration deployments to understand changes and assess production impact
- Extract and analyze data from APIs and translate data-driven insight into decisions that improve customer experience
- Develop technical documentation for operations team and deliver presentations on operational matters to peers and executives

# SKILLS

| Python                                |
|---------------------------------------|
|                                       |
| SQL                                   |
| Splunk                                |
|                                       |
| Business Intelligence / Visualization |
|                                       |
| Spark                                 |
|                                       |
| Hadoop                                |
| Linux                                 |
|                                       |
| Automation                            |
|                                       |
| Video Transcoding                     |
|                                       |

# **EDUCATION**

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE / COMPUTER SCIENCE WEST CHESTER UNIVERSITY. West Chester, PA | 1998-2002

# JUSTIN NALDZIN

# **WORK EXPERIENCE CONTINUED**

VIDEO & DATA ANALYTICS LEAD

Comcast | Philadelphia | March 2011 - October 2015

Responsible for data metrics and reporting of the entire Video Operations value chain.

- Develop scripts and utilities to automate data collection from APIs and databases
- Produce time-series charts and dashboards for ingest volume, encoding efficiency, and track storage usage and capacity
- Identify patterns and trends in data and implement corrective solutions to maximize efficiency and improve user experience
- Alert on server task failures within publishing workflow
- Ensure accuracy and optimize performance of data stores
- Serve as a reporting liaison between the content team, data integration team, product owners, and senior management to communicate technical findings

#### SENIOR VIDEO SPECIALIST

Comcast Interactive Media | Philadelphia | September 2006 - March 2011

Extensive knowledge of analog and digital video transcoding technologies using SD/HD video formats, NTSC standards and CableLabs specifications.

- Adaptive bitrate streaming: Apple HLS, Adobe HDS, Microsoft Smooth Streaming
- Streaming media protocols: HTTP, RTMPE
- Video/audio codecs and compression: H.264, MPEG, VP6, MP3, AC-3, AAC
- Container formats: FLV, MOV, AVI, 3GP, MPEG-2 TS
- Networking technologies: TCP/IP, DNS, AFP, SMB

# **REFERENCES**



CHRIS HOLLISTER

MANAGER

Comcast

Christopher\_Hollister@comcast.com



SCOTT MCGILL

MANAGER

Comcast

Scott McGill@comcast.com

## **EXPERTISE**

## SCRIPTING & DEVELOPMENT LANGUAGES:

 Python (Pandas, NumPy), Scala, Ruby, PHP, bash, HTML, JavaScript, CSS

#### DATA SCIENCE:

• Spark SQL, Hadoop, Hive, Cassandra

#### **DATA STORES:**

• Oracle, SQL Server, MySQL, MariaDB, HANA

#### **OPERATING SYSTEMS:**

 Red Hat Enterprise Linux, CentOS, macOS, Windows

## VIRTUALIZATION TECHNOLOGIES:

• OpenStack, VirtualBox, VMware

#### CONFIGURATION MANAGEMENT:

• Vagrant, Docker, Puppet

## MONITORING & ALERTING:

• Nagios, Zabbix

## BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE:

• Splunk, Tableau, Lumira

## AGILE PROJECT TRACKING:

• Jira, Rally

## **VERSION CONTROL AND INTEGRATION TOOLS:**

· Git, GitHub, Jenkins

#### OTHER RELEVANT KNOWLEDGE:

 Splunk Certified Knowledge Manager, Elemental, Aspera, CDN, NetApp, HDFS, CableLabs, XML, JSON, RESTful Web Services

# **SOCIAL MEDIA**



YOUTUBE.COM/JUSTINNALDZIN



FACEBOOK.COM/JUSTINNALDZIN



TWITTER.COM/JUSTINNALDZIN